Instructions: For your final project, you will build a user registration website. The website must contain both the client side (file components: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript) and the server side (file components: PHP, and MySQL database provided by the XAMPP application). On the client side, it is expected that you will display the following form inputs:

First Name
Last Name
Birthday
Gender
Email Address
Password
Confirm Password

Register (button)

Additionally, you need to incorporate JavaScript to your user registration page and perform the following: 
• Check if input values are not empty. 
• Check if Password and Confirm Password are of the same value. 
• Check if the format of the Email address is correct

Lastly, be creative in building your website. You may choose what type of design to incorporate into your website, as long as you adhere to the principles of web design, such as hierarchy, alignment, and color. 

For the server side, ensure that you have installed the XAMPP application. After installation, open the XAMPP control panel and start the servers to establish a connection between your website and the web server. (Note that you cannot execute PHP if the XAMPP server is not running). 

The PHP file is responsible for handling the form submission and storing the user input in the MySQL database. Ensure that you connect your website to the database before handling the form. After connecting to the database, retrieve all the input values from the user registration page. The PHP should retrieve the following inputs: 
• First Name 
• Last Name 
• Birthday 
• Gender 
• Email address 
• Password 

These values are then saved to your MySQL database. If the operation is successful, the PHP will respond with "User successfully added to the database." Otherwise, it should respond with "Failed to add user to the database”.


save these links:
http://localhost/phpmyadmin/index.php
http://localhost/index.html
http://localhost/phpmyadmin/index.php?route=/sql&pos=0&db=registration_db&table=users

syntax to delete data from the table:
DELETE FROM users; 

If your site is not live yet, and you just want to update the stylesheet at your pleased intervals, then use this: 

On Windows Ctrl + F5

On Mac OS (in Chrome) use: Cmd + Shift + R.

